<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RTL on My second brain</title>
    <link>https://iblogging.github.io/tags/rtl/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RTL on My second brain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iblogging.github.io/tags/rtl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Vivado for Software Engineers</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-11-intro-to-vivado-for-software-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-11-intro-to-vivado-for-software-engineers/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Intro to Vivado for Software Engineers Main Source Intro to Vivado for Software Engineers Author Neil Turley Other references:
https://digilent.com/reference/programmable-logic/guides/vivado-xdc-file Source Files two types of source files:
HDL: defines the logic constraints: pin locations provided by board provider as xdc file Tips: Search for xdc file Intel FPGA: qsf file Contrains xdc example: top.xdc set_property -dict { PACKAGE_PIN E3 IOSTANDARD LVCMOS33 } [get_ports { clk100mhz }]; create_clock -add -name sys_clk_pin -period 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDR3 SDRAM Test by Nios II</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-08-ddr3-sdram-test-by-nios-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-08-ddr3-sdram-test-by-nios-ii/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject DDR3 SDRAM Test by Nios II Main Source DDR3 SDRAM Test by Nios II Other references:
https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/programmable/customertraining/ILT/PDF/A-MNL-ISDMI-ALL-12-0-v1.pdf Many applications use a high performance RAM, such as a DDR3 SDRAM, to provide temporary storage. This post show:
how the Altera’s “DDR3 SDRAM Controller with UniPHY” IP is used to access a DDR3-SDRAM, and how the Nios II processor is used to read and write the SDRAM for hardware verification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finite State Machine</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-05-finite-state-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-05-finite-state-machine/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Finite State Machine Main Source Finite State Machine Author Daniel E. Gisselquist A finite state machine consists of Inputs State Variable Finite means there are a limited number of states Outputs Two classical FSM forms Mealy Moore Two implementation approaches One process Two process Mealy Outputs depend upon the current state inputs always @ ( ∗ ) if (!i_display_enable ) o_led = 0 ; else case ( led_index ) 4&amp;#39;h1 : o_led = 8&amp;#39;h01 ; 4&amp;#39;h2 : o_led = 8&amp;#39;h02 ; 4&amp;#39;h3 : o_led = 8&amp;#39;h04 ; 4&amp;#39;h4 : o_led = 8&amp;#39;h08 ; // .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registers and blinky</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-05-registers-and-blinky/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-05-registers-and-blinky/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Registers and blinky Main Source Registers and blinky Author Daniel E. Gisselquist Registers Why use registers? Wires have no memory Only registers can hold state (data) Two basic types, both set with an always Combinatorial:
Like wires always @ ( ∗ ) A = B ; This form can be easier to read when the logic becomes complex Synchronous:
Only changes values on a clock always @ ( posedge i_clk ) A &amp;lt;= B ; Combinatorial Regs always @ ( ∗ ) A = 9&amp;#39;h87 ; Registers can only be assigned in always blocks Always blocks may consist of one statement, or Many statements between a begin and end pair always @(∗) begin o_led = A ˆ i_sw ; o_led = o_led + 7 ; if( i_reset) o_led = 0 ; end Looks like software Acts like you would expect in a simulator Takes no time at all in hardware The hardware acts as if all statements were done at once Latches and Last Assignment Wins Flip Flops reg [9:0] A ; always @ ( posedge i_clk ) A &amp;lt;= A + 1&amp;#39;b1 ; Any registers set within an always @(posedge i_clk) block will transitions to their new values on the next clock edge only Only a bonafide clock edge should be used Do not transition on anything you create in logic Non-Blocking always @ ( posedge i_clk ) begin A &amp;lt;= 5 ; A &amp;lt;= A + 1 ’ b1 ; end Assume, A starts with 0 The assignment only takes place on the clock edge Last assignment wins &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; A is set to 1, then 2 on the next clock, 3 on the clock after Blocking always @ ( posedge i_clk ) begin A = 5 ; A = A + 1&amp;#39;b1 ; end the assignment only takes place on the clock edge It appears as though it took several steps A is set to 6 other examples Assume A=0 before the clock tick always @ ( posedge i_clk ) begin A &amp;lt;= 5 ; // I g n o r e d !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wires, and combinatorial logic</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-wires-and-combinatorial-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-wires-and-combinatorial-logic/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Wires, and combinatorial logic Main Source Wires, and combinatorial logic Author Daniel E. Gisselquist First design module thruwire ( i_sw , o_led ) ; input wire i_sw ; output wire o_led ; assign o_led = i_sw ; endmodule This module declares two ports,
i_sw and o_led Our one piece of logic sets o_led to be the same as i_sw
Schematic A very similar design would make a good first serial port test Your circuit board should pass this test before you try to implement your own serial port within it</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-verilog-formal-verification-and-verilator-beginner-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-verilog-formal-verification-and-verilator-beginner-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial Main Source Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial Author Daniel E. Gisselquist 1. Wires, and combinatorial logic 2. Registers and blinky 3. Finite state machines 4. Building a Wishbone Slave 5. Building hello world, using a serial port transmitter 6. Transmitting 32-bit data over the serial port 7. Buttons: 2FF synchronizers, and debouncing 8. Using FPGA block RAM 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Gisselquist&#39;s FPGA debugging philosophy</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-dan-gisselquist-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-dan-gisselquist-debug/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Dan Gisselquist&amp;rsquo;s FPGA debugging philosophy Main Source Dan Gisselquist&amp;rsquo;s FPGA debugging philosophy Author Zip CPU 1. Simulation Ability to simulate all of the external components on the design 2. Hardware testing component testing Issuing individual commands to them, and verifying that individual interactions work Then issuing more complex strings of commands integrated design testing How to Debug an FPGA Start with blinky. Use blinky to debug FPGA Learn to use simulation A Vision for controlling (and debugging) an FPGA Getting that first UART working Debugging by simple bus address, Building a debug control interface How to place a logic analyzer within your design, and to get the most use out of it Getting rid of the umbilical: moving your debugging channel to TCP/IP </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Actual FPGA Design Process</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-the-actual-fpga-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-the-actual-fpga-design-process/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject The Actual FPGA Design Process Main Source The Actual FPGA Design Process Author Zip CPU The Student’s FPGA Design Process The student builds his design in Verilog He then implements it on an FPGA, adjusting his design as necessary to meet timing and build requirements The design is then placed onto the FPGA for a test, and … The student can’t figure out why it isn’t working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a simple bus</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-building-simple-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-building-simple-bus/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Building a simple bus Main Source Building a simple bus Author Zip CPU Bus ### Bues - Masters + issue a command which addresses need to be + read from or + written to - Slaves + respond to the requests of the bus master(s) Simple bus Three things can only ever happen on this bus on any given clock cycle.
The vast majority of the time, the bus will be idle You might write to the bus or you might read from the bus Signals i_wr: True any time a write is requested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-a-vision-for-controlling-fpga-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-a-vision-for-controlling-fpga-logic/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic Main Source A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic Author Zip CPU Memory Mapped I/O # Memory Mapped I/O - Peripherals can be connected to a bus + they can be accessed like memory + may have many addresses + may take different amounts of time to access. - Bus controller + type + CPU + [DMA peripheral](https://github.com/ZipCPU/zipcpu/blob/master/rtl/peripherals/wbdmac.v) + write to the peripheral + read from it - Register + a single address + within a peripheral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Hell</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-fpga-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-fpga-hell/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject FPGA Hell Main Source FPGA Hell Author Zip CPU FPGA Hell: load the design onto device, it doesn’t work, and you don’t know why.
## The solution - Level 1: Simulation + Simulate everything + Run on similation first. + use the simulation to debug + If the issue can not be resolve, use `scope` - Level 2: Scope + Measure what’s really going on + Watch your code interact with the real hardware, and + use what you learn to `find where reality and your simulation disconnect`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-02/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic Main Source AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic Author Stephen St. Michael The ready/valid hardware data transfer protocol is simple and ingenious, providing flow control with only two control signals. The rules are straightforward: data transfer only happens when both ready and valid are &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; during the same clock cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI)</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-01/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI) Main Source Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI) Author Stephen St. Michael The AXI Architecture AXI Channels - AXI Channels - Read address channel - Read data channel - Write address channel - Write data channel - Write response channel The address channels are used to send
address and control information while performing a basic handshake between master and slave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-how-axi-style-ready-valid-handshake-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-how-axi-style-ready-valid-handshake-work/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS Main Source HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS Author JONAS JULIAN JENSEN The ready/valid hardware data transfer protocol is simple and ingenious, providing flow control with only two control signals. The rules are straightforward: data transfer only happens when both ready and valid are &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; during the same clock cycle.
USING THE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE RECEIVER AND SENDER INTERFAC CONNECTING TWO MODULES Examples SENDING AND RECEIVING AT FULL SPEED SLOW WRITER AND FAST READER In this example, the ready signal is always &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; while the sender asserts valid occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Building Blocks</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-8/</guid>
      <description>1. Module A module is a block of Verilog code that implements a certain functionality. Modules can be embedded within other modules and a higher level module can communicate with its lower level modules using their input and output ports. A module should be enclosed within module and endmodule keywords module &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; ([port_list]); // Contents of the module endmodule // A module can have an empty portlist module name; // Contents of the module endmodule // Module called &amp;#34;dff&amp;#34; has 3 inputs and 1 output port module dff ( input d, input clk, input rstn, output reg	q); // Contents of the module always @ (posedge clk) begin if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Arrays and Memories</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-7/</guid>
      <description>An array declaration of a net or variable can be either scalar or vector. multi-dimensional array address range identifier reg y1 [11:0]; // y is an scalar reg array of depth=12, each 1-bit wide wire [0:7] y2 [3:0] // y is an 8-bit vector net with a depth of 4 reg [7:0] y3 [0:1][0:3]; // y is a 2D array rows=2,cols=4 each 8-bit wide Assignment y1 = 0; // Illegal - All elements can&amp;#39;t be assigned in a single go y2[0] = 8&amp;#39;ha2; // Assign 0xa2 to index=0 y2[2] = 8&amp;#39;h1c; // Assign 0x1c to index=2 y3[1][2] = 8&amp;#39;hdd; // Assign 0xdd to rows=1 cols=2 y3[0][0] = 8&amp;#39;haa; // Assign 0xaa to rows=0 cols=0 Example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog scalar and vector</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Scalar and Vector A net or reg declaration without a range specification is considered 1-bit wide and is a scalar. If a range is specified, then the net or reg becomes a multibit entity known as a vector. wire o_nor; // single bit scalar net wire [7:0] o_flop; // 8-bit vector net reg parity; // single bit scalar variable reg [31:0] addr; // 32 bit vector variable to store address Bit-selects Any bit in a vectored variable can be individually selected and assigned a new value reg [7:0] addr; // 8-bit reg variable [7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0] addr [0] = 1; // assign 1 to bit 0 of addr addr [3] = 0; // assign 0 to bit 3 of addr addr [8] = 1; // illegal : bit8 does not exist in addr Part-selects A range of contiguous bits can be selected and is known as a part-select constant part-select indexed part-select reg [31:0] addr; addr [23:16] = 8&amp;#39;h23; // bits 23 to 16 will be replaced by the new value &amp;#39;h23 -&amp;gt; constant part-select [&amp;lt;start_bit&amp;gt; +: &amp;lt;width&amp;gt;] // part-select increments from start-bit [&amp;lt;start_bit&amp;gt; -: &amp;lt;width&amp;gt;] // part-select decrements from start-bit module des; reg [31:0] data; int i; initial begin data = 32&amp;#39;hFACE_CAFE; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; 4; i++) begin $display (&amp;#34;data[8*%0d +: 8] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, i, data[8*i +: 8]); end $display (&amp;#34;data[7:0] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[7:0]); $display (&amp;#34;data[15:8] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[15:8]); $display (&amp;#34;data[23:16] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[23:16]); $display (&amp;#34;data[31:24] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[31:24]); end endmodule Source https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Data Types</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-5/</guid>
      <description>What values do variables hold ? Almost all data-types can only have one of the four different values as given below except for real and event data types.
Type Meaning 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state What does the verilog value-set imply ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog syntax</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Operators Unary operators shall appear to the left of their operand Binary operators shall appear between their operands Conditional operators have two separate operators that separate three operands x = ~y; // ~ is a unary operator, and y is the operand x = y | z; // | is a binary operator, where y and z are its operands // If the expression (y &amp;gt; 5) is true, then variable x will get the value in w, else the value in z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASIC Design Flow</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Source https://www.chipverify.com/verilog/asic-soc-chip-design-flow </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Verilog</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A digital element such as a flip-flop can be represented with combinational gates like NAND and NOR The functionality of a flip-flop is achieved by the connection of a certain set of gates in a particular manner How the gates have to be connected is usually figured out by solving K-map from the truth table The truth table is nothing but a table that tells us what inputs combine together to give what values of output Shown in the image below is an electronic circuit that represents a D-flip flop and the corresponding truth table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Verilog - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the early days of integrated circuits, engineers had to sit down and physically draw transistors and their connections on paper to design them such that it can be fabricated on silicon.
Bigger and complex circuits demanded more engineers, time and other resources and soon enough there was a need to have a better way of designing integrated circuits.
VHDL was soon developed to enhance the design process by allowing engineers to describe functionality of the desired hardware and let automation tools convert that behavior into actual hardware elements like combinational gates and sequential logic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
