<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My second brain</title>
    <link>https://iblogging.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My second brain</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iblogging.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-verilog-formal-verification-and-verilator-beginner-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-verilog-formal-verification-and-verilator-beginner-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial Main Source Verilog, Formal Verification and Verilator Beginner Tutorial Author Zip CPU 1. Wires, and combinatorial logic First design module thruwire ( i_sw , o_led ) ; input wire i_sw ; output wire o_led ; assign o_led = i_sw ; endmodule This module declares two ports,
i_sw and o_led Our one piece of logic sets o_led to be the same as i_sw</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Gisselquist&#39;s FPGA debugging philosophy</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-dan-gisselquist-debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-dan-gisselquist-debug/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Dan Gisselquist&amp;rsquo;s FPGA debugging philosophy Main Source Dan Gisselquist&amp;rsquo;s FPGA debugging philosophy Author Zip CPU 1. Simulation Ability to simulate all of the external components on the design 2. Hardware testing component testing Issuing individual commands to them, and verifying that individual interactions work Then issuing more complex strings of commands integrated design testing How to Debug an FPGA Start with blinky. Use blinky to debug FPGA Learn to use simulation A Vision for controlling (and debugging) an FPGA Getting that first UART working Debugging by simple bus address, Building a debug control interface How to place a logic analyzer within your design, and to get the most use out of it Getting rid of the umbilical: moving your debugging channel to TCP/IP </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Actual FPGA Design Process</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-the-actual-fpga-design-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-the-actual-fpga-design-process/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject The Actual FPGA Design Process Main Source The Actual FPGA Design Process Author Zip CPU The Student’s FPGA Design Process The student builds his design in Verilog He then implements it on an FPGA, adjusting his design as necessary to meet timing and build requirements The design is then placed onto the FPGA for a test, and … The student can’t figure out why it isn’t working.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a simple bus</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-building-simple-bus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-building-simple-bus/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Building a simple bus Main Source Building a simple bus Author Zip CPU Bus ### Bues - Masters + issue a command which addresses need to be + read from or + written to - Slaves + respond to the requests of the bus master(s) Simple bus Three things can only ever happen on this bus on any given clock cycle.
The vast majority of the time, the bus will be idle You might write to the bus or you might read from the bus Signals i_wr: True any time a write is requested.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-a-vision-for-controlling-fpga-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-a-vision-for-controlling-fpga-logic/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic Main Source A Vision for Controlling FPGA Logic Author Zip CPU Memory Mapped I/O # Memory Mapped I/O - Peripherals can be connected to a bus + they can be accessed like memory + may have many addresses + may take different amounts of time to access. - Bus controller + type + CPU + [DMA peripheral](https://github.com/ZipCPU/zipcpu/blob/master/rtl/peripherals/wbdmac.v) + write to the peripheral + read from it - Register + a single address + within a peripheral.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA Hell</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-fpga-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-fpga-hell/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject FPGA Hell Main Source FPGA Hell Author Zip CPU FPGA Hell: load the design onto device, it doesn’t work, and you don’t know why.
## The solution - Level 1: Simulation + Simulate everything + Run on similation first. + use the simulation to debug + If the issue can not be resolve, use `scope` - Level 2: Scope + Measure what’s really going on + Watch your code interact with the real hardware, and + use what you learn to `find where reality and your simulation disconnect`.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-02/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic Main Source AXI Interconnects Tutorial: Multiple AXI Masters and Slaves in Digital Logic Author Stephen St. Michael The ready/valid hardware data transfer protocol is simple and ingenious, providing flow control with only two control signals. The rules are straightforward: data transfer only happens when both ready and valid are &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; during the same clock cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI)</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-axi-interconnects-tutorial-01/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI) Main Source Introduction to the Advanced Extensible Interface (AXI) Author Stephen St. Michael The AXI Architecture AXI Channels - AXI Channels - Read address channel - Read data channel - Write address channel - Write data channel - Write response channel The address channels are used to send
address and control information while performing a basic handshake between master and slave.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-how-axi-style-ready-valid-handshake-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-how-axi-style-ready-valid-handshake-work/</guid>
      <description>Learning sources Attribute Detail Subject HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS Main Source HOW THE AXI-STYLE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE WORKS Author JONAS JULIAN JENSEN The ready/valid hardware data transfer protocol is simple and ingenious, providing flow control with only two control signals. The rules are straightforward: data transfer only happens when both ready and valid are &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; during the same clock cycle.
USING THE READY/VALID HANDSHAKE RECEIVER AND SENDER INTERFAC CONNECTING TWO MODULES Examples SENDING AND RECEIVING AT FULL SPEED SLOW WRITER AND FAST READER In this example, the ready signal is always &amp;lsquo;1&amp;rsquo; while the sender asserts valid occasionally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longest Prefix Matching in Networking Chips</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-longest-prefix-matching-in-networking-chips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-04-longest-prefix-matching-in-networking-chips/</guid>
      <description>Attribute Detail Subject Longest Prefix Matching in Networking Chips Source Longest Prefix Matching in Networking Chips Source Longest Prefix Match with Trie Tree Author Sharada Yeluri Basics Two planes Control plane
determine how the packets should be processed and forwarded. executes these tasks in the background populates the tables in the data plane maintains Routing Information Database (RIB) routes direct routes static routes dynamic routes Control plane software optimizes and compresses the information in the RIB before installing the routes into the tables inside networking chips ( called Forwarding Information Databases (FIB) ) Forwarding Information Databases (FIB) stored in on-chip or off-chip memories (SRAM, HBM/DRAM, or TCAM) contains just enough information to forward the packets to their next destination or nexthop updated by the control plane software Contents contains the IP address subnet mask (or IP prefix), and the nexthop could directly indicate the physical interface Or it can point to an entry in yet another table Simplest model Data plane or forwarding plane</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Write Linux PCI Drivers</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/linux/2022-10-02-how-to-write-pci-driver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/linux/2022-10-02-how-to-write-pci-driver/</guid>
      <description>The PCI bus is the most popular way to connect high-speed peripheral inside a modern computer system:
a video and network adapters, sound cards, storage devices, etc. Some custom and special devices, some acquisition boards with ADC, or any other interface might be custom and special devices. Even your modern laptop uses this bus to connect internal devices to the CPU, even without actual physical connectors. This bus is widely available on a different platforms, like x86, arm, mips, riscv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fact over fake</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-fact-over-fake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-fact-over-fake/</guid>
      <description>Fact over fake 1. KEY CRITICAL THINKING QUESTIONS TO ASK WHEN SEEKING THE NEWS Is this news source reputable? In other words: Does it appear to at least attempt to present the news in an unbiased manner? Does it have a track record of reporting actual stories, rather than urban myths, conspiracy theories, and other unfounded claims? Does this news source openly publish retractions and corrections after making errors in its reporting?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Critical Thinking</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-the-spirit-of-critial-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-the-spirit-of-critial-thinking/</guid>
      <description>The Spirit of Critical Thinking Template for Analyzing the Logic of an Article Use this template to deconstruct any article, essay, or chapter of a textbook.
The Logic of “(name of the article)” 1. The main purpose of this article is ________________________________. State as accurately as possible the author’s purpose for writing the article. 2. The key question that the author is addressing is ____________________. Figure out the key question in the mind of the author when s/he wrote the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elements of Thought</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-critical-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-critical-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Element of thoughts Whenever we think, we think for
a purpose within a point of view based on assumptions that lead to implications and consequences. We use
concepts, ideas, and theories to interpret data, facts, and experiences in order to
answer questions, solve problems, and resolve issues. Questions Using the Elements of Thoughts Purpose What am I trying to accomplish? What is my central aim? My purpose? Questions What question am I raising?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book list</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-boolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-boolist/</guid>
      <description> Book Summary 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Book</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-how-to-read-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-how-to-read-a-book/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two kind of books:
Fiction/novels books Non-fiction books textbooks manuals journal articles histories academic studies etc The purpose of reading things like Non-fiction books is to gain, and retain, information finding out what happens — as quickly and easily as possible — is your main goal
NEVER read a non-fiction book or article from beginning to end
Strategy should ALWAYS jump ahead skip around use every available strategy to discover, then to understand and finally to remember what the writer has to say you should be able to read a 300-page book in 06 to 08 hours</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feedback: Key to Continuous Learning</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-feedback/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-feedback/</guid>
      <description>Drucker on Asia - Peter Drucker Feedback: Key to Continuous Learning To know one’s strengths, to know how to improve them, and to know what one cannot do—are the keys to continuous learning. Whenever a Jesuit priest or a Calvinist pastor does anything of significance (for instance, making a key decision)
he is expected to write down what results he anticipates. Nine months later, he then feeds back from the actual results to these anticipations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinvent Yourself</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-reinvent-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-reinvent-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Drucker on Asia - Peter Drucker Knowledge people must take responsibility for their own development and placement In today’s society and organizations, people work increasingly with knowledge, rather than with skill.
Knowledge and skill differ in a fundamental characteristic: skills change very, very slowly. Knowledge, however,changes itself. It makes itself obsolete, and very rapidly. A knowledge worker becomes obsolescent [nerver use] if he or she does not go back to school every three or four years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefit and Manner of Asking the Right</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-asking-the-right-questions-c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-asking-the-right-questions-c1/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 Objective Contrast a world where no critical thinking is needed with the world we live in. Understand the role of experts in forming our beliefs and conclusions. Clarify the meaning of critical thinking. Distinguish between weak-sense and strong-sense critical thinking. Integrate the role of values with critical thinking. Identify techniques for using critical thinking as a conversation stimulus. This is a colour shortcode &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot; background-color: red; -webkit-background-clip: text; -moz-background-clip: text; background-clip: text; color: transparent; &amp;quot; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Building Blocks</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-8/</guid>
      <description>1. Module A module is a block of Verilog code that implements a certain functionality. Modules can be embedded within other modules and a higher level module can communicate with its lower level modules using their input and output ports. A module should be enclosed within module and endmodule keywords module &amp;lt;name&amp;gt; ([port_list]); // Contents of the module endmodule // A module can have an empty portlist module name; // Contents of the module endmodule // Module called &amp;#34;dff&amp;#34; has 3 inputs and 1 output port module dff ( input d, input clk, input rstn, output reg	q); // Contents of the module always @ (posedge clk) begin if (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Understand shire</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-understand-shire-source-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-understand-shire-source-code/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Shire is a new approach to designing FPGA-accelerated middleboxes that
simplifies development, debugging, and performance tuning by decoupling the tasks of hardware accelerator implementation and software application programming Architecture Shire includes 04 main components
IO ports for packet input/output. 100Gbps Ethernet ports to transmit packets to the network 100Gbps PCIe port to transmit packets and control message with host Packet scheduler Distribute packets to Packet processing units IO ports Packet switch As a queue to deliver packets between Packet Processor and Packet Scheduler Packet processor RISC-V core Accelerator Hybrid memory subsystem IO Ports 100Gbps Ethernet 100Gps PCIe Packet scheduler (PS) Externally, the PS module need to comminicate with 03 other modules</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5 Whys mental model</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/mental-models/2022-09-29-5-whys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/mental-models/2022-09-29-5-whys/</guid>
      <description>Introduction By asking why multiple times we can have a deeper understanding on the causes of the higher level problem. The goal is to land on a what or a how.
It’s an interrogative technique that’s iterative, and is used to discover the root causes of a problem. The answer to each “why” question leads to an answer that forms the basis of the next question.
The “five” in the name comes from the observation that it often takes about 5 iterations to get to the root cause of a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Arrays and Memories</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-7/</guid>
      <description>An array declaration of a net or variable can be either scalar or vector. multi-dimensional array address range identifier reg y1 [11:0]; // y is an scalar reg array of depth=12, each 1-bit wide wire [0:7] y2 [3:0] // y is an 8-bit vector net with a depth of 4 reg [7:0] y3 [0:1][0:3]; // y is a 2D array rows=2,cols=4 each 8-bit wide Assignment y1 = 0; // Illegal - All elements can&amp;#39;t be assigned in a single go y2[0] = 8&amp;#39;ha2; // Assign 0xa2 to index=0 y2[2] = 8&amp;#39;h1c; // Assign 0x1c to index=2 y3[1][2] = 8&amp;#39;hdd; // Assign 0xdd to rows=1 cols=2 y3[0][0] = 8&amp;#39;haa; // Assign 0xaa to rows=0 cols=0 Example</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog scalar and vector</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-6/</guid>
      <description>Scalar and Vector A net or reg declaration without a range specification is considered 1-bit wide and is a scalar. If a range is specified, then the net or reg becomes a multibit entity known as a vector. wire o_nor; // single bit scalar net wire [7:0] o_flop; // 8-bit vector net reg parity; // single bit scalar variable reg [31:0] addr; // 32 bit vector variable to store address Bit-selects Any bit in a vectored variable can be individually selected and assigned a new value reg [7:0] addr; // 8-bit reg variable [7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, 0] addr [0] = 1; // assign 1 to bit 0 of addr addr [3] = 0; // assign 0 to bit 3 of addr addr [8] = 1; // illegal : bit8 does not exist in addr Part-selects A range of contiguous bits can be selected and is known as a part-select constant part-select indexed part-select reg [31:0] addr; addr [23:16] = 8&amp;#39;h23; // bits 23 to 16 will be replaced by the new value &amp;#39;h23 -&amp;gt; constant part-select [&amp;lt;start_bit&amp;gt; +: &amp;lt;width&amp;gt;] // part-select increments from start-bit [&amp;lt;start_bit&amp;gt; -: &amp;lt;width&amp;gt;] // part-select decrements from start-bit module des; reg [31:0] data; int i; initial begin data = 32&amp;#39;hFACE_CAFE; for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; 4; i++) begin $display (&amp;#34;data[8*%0d +: 8] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, i, data[8*i +: 8]); end $display (&amp;#34;data[7:0] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[7:0]); $display (&amp;#34;data[15:8] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[15:8]); $display (&amp;#34;data[23:16] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[23:16]); $display (&amp;#34;data[31:24] = 0x%0h&amp;#34;, data[31:24]); end endmodule Source https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog Data Types</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-5/</guid>
      <description>What values do variables hold ? Almost all data-types can only have one of the four different values as given below except for real and event data types.
Type Meaning 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state What does the verilog value-set imply ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verilog syntax</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 19:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Operators Unary operators shall appear to the left of their operand Binary operators shall appear between their operands Conditional operators have two separate operators that separate three operands x = ~y; // ~ is a unary operator, and y is the operand x = y | z; // | is a binary operator, where y and z are its operands // If the expression (y &amp;gt; 5) is true, then variable x will get the value in w, else the value in z.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASIC Design Flow</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Source https://www.chipverify.com/verilog/asic-soc-chip-design-flow </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Verilog</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A digital element such as a flip-flop can be represented with combinational gates like NAND and NOR The functionality of a flip-flop is achieved by the connection of a certain set of gates in a particular manner How the gates have to be connected is usually figured out by solving K-map from the truth table The truth table is nothing but a table that tells us what inputs combine together to give what values of output Shown in the image below is an electronic circuit that represents a D-flip flop and the corresponding truth table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Shire, 200 Gbps middlebox framework for FPGAs</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-shire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-shire/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Shire is a new approach to designing FPGA-accelerated middleboxes that
simplifies development, debugging, and performance tuning by decoupling the tasks of hardware accelerator implementation and software application programming Prerequisites Vivado Intel Quartus RISC-V toolchain Partial Reconfiguration tools Xilinx: MCAP driver Intel Altera Building FPGA image For each board: define the number of RPU Current implementation 256 packets stored in buffer 16 RPU &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Slots = 256/16 = 16 8 RPU &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Slots = 256/8 = 32 Check Makefile on how to swapping PR regions with the desired accelerator For example fpga_src/boards/VCU1525_200g_8G make to build base image make base_0 base_0 is the base image with static regions make PIG_Hash_1 add Pigasus string matching accelerator to the RPUs make PIG_base_2 only update the load balancer to be round robin without changing the RPUs from the base design make PIG_RR_3 merge the first two, meaning taking the RPUs from PIG_Hash_1 and load balancer from PIG_base_2 Adding accelerators accelerators Examples pigasus_sme Ported Pigasus string matcher accelerator hash a hash accelerator for TCP/UDP headers ip_matcher from-scratch firewall accelerator Connect accelerator to RPU use the Verilog interface provided in the accelerator wrapper\ fpga_src/accel/ip_matcher/rtl/accel_wrap_firewall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture of reconfigurable systems</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-architecture-of-reconfigurable-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-architecture-of-reconfigurable-systems/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is my notes on studying Architecture of reconfigurable systems from Prof Jordane Lorandel. The course includes 03 main parts:
FPGA introduction SoC introduction Partial Reconfiguration introduction </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture of reconfigurable systems - FPGA</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-fpga/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-fpga/</guid>
      <description>Digital Hardware Design: Two approaches An introduction to FPGAs FPGAs Reconfigurable Mean not defined after manufacture, could be specified by the programmers themselves Configuration types Static Reconfiguration Load the whole bitstream on the FPGA Stop the execution to do the loading Static Partial Reconfiguration Only a portion of the bitstream is loaded on the FPGA Stop the execution to load the partial iage but the wait time is much shorter Dynamic Partial Reconfiguration Part of the FPGA is reconfigured while the rest is still running How is ensure reconfiguration?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study Verilog - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-29-verilog-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In the early days of integrated circuits, engineers had to sit down and physically draw transistors and their connections on paper to design them such that it can be fabricated on silicon.
Bigger and complex circuits demanded more engineers, time and other resources and soon enough there was a need to have a better way of designing integrated circuits.
VHDL was soon developed to enhance the design process by allowing engineers to describe functionality of the desired hardware and let automation tools convert that behavior into actual hardware elements like combinational gates and sequential logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/readme/</guid>
      <description>TIPS 1. UML @startuml Alice -&amp;gt; Bob: Authentication Request Bob --&amp;gt; Alice: Authentication Response Alice -&amp;gt; Bob: Another authentication Request Alice &amp;lt;-- Bob: Another authentication Response @enduml 2. Mindmap Root Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 3 Level 3 Level 4 Level 5 Level 6 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Table Type Meaning 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state Color Knowledge people must take responsibility for their own development and placement Add comments https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FPGA designs with Verilog</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-01-fpga-designs-with-verilog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/fpga/2022-10-01-fpga-designs-with-verilog/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/notes/</guid>
      <description>TIPS 1. UML @startumlAlice -&amp;gt; Bob: Authentication RequestBob --&amp;gt; Alice: Authentication ResponseAlice -&amp;gt; Bob: Another authentication RequestAlice &amp;lt;-- Bob: Another authentication Response@enduml 2. Mindmap Root Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 3 Level 3 Level 4 Level 5 Level 6 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Level 1 Level 2 Level 2 Table Type Meaning 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state Color Knowledge people must take responsibility for their own development and placement Add comments https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
