<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book on Lap Blog</title>
    <link>https://iblogging.github.io/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book on Lap Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iblogging.github.io/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Spirit of Critical Thinking</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-the-spirit-of-critial-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-the-spirit-of-critial-thinking/</guid>
      <description>The Spirit of Critical Thinking Template for Analyzing the Logic of an Article Use this template to deconstruct any article, essay, or chapter of a textbook.
The Logic of “(name of the article)” 1. The main purpose of this article is ________________________________. State as accurately as possible the author’s purpose for writing the article. 2. The key question that the author is addressing is ____________________. Figure out the key question in the mind of the author when s/he wrote the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Elements of Thought</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-critical-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-critical-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Element of thoughts Whenever we think, we think for
a purpose within a point of view based on assumptions that lead to implications and consequences. We use
concepts, ideas, and theories to interpret data, facts, and experiences in order to
answer questions, solve problems, and resolve issues. Questions Using the Elements of Thoughts Purpose What am I trying to accomplish? What is my central aim? My purpose? Questions What question am I raising?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book list</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-boolist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-boolist/</guid>
      <description> Book Summary 0 represents a logic zero, or a false condition 1 represents a logic one, or a true condition x represents an unknown logic value (can be zero or one) z represents a high-impedance state </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Read a Book</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-how-to-read-a-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/books/2022-10-01-how-to-read-a-book/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Two kind of books:
Fiction/novels books Non-fiction books textbooks manuals journal articles histories academic studies etc The purpose of reading things like Non-fiction books is to gain, and retain, information finding out what happens — as quickly and easily as possible — is your main goal
NEVER read a non-fiction book or article from beginning to end
Strategy should ALWAYS jump ahead skip around use every available strategy to discover, then to understand and finally to remember what the writer has to say you should be able to read a 300-page book in 06 to 08 hours</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
