<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mental models on Lap Blog</title>
    <link>https://iblogging.github.io/tags/mental-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mental models on Lap Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://iblogging.github.io/tags/mental-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reinvent Yourself</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-reinvent-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/2022-09-30-reinvent-yourself/</guid>
      <description>Drucker on Asia - Peter Drucker Knowledge people must take responsibility for their own development and placement
In today’s society and organizations, people work increasingly with knowledge, rather than with skill.
Knowledge and skill differ in a fundamental characteristic
skills change very, very slowly. Knowledge, however,changes itself. It makes itself obsolete, and very rapidly. A knowledge worker becomes obsolescent [nerver use] if he or she does not go back to school every three or four years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> 5 Whys mental model</title>
      <link>https://iblogging.github.io/post/mental-models/2022-09-29-5-whys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://iblogging.github.io/post/mental-models/2022-09-29-5-whys/</guid>
      <description>Introduction By asking why multiple times we can have a deeper understanding on the causes of the higher level problem. The goal is to land on a what or a how.
It’s an interrogative technique that’s iterative, and is used to discover the root causes of a problem. The answer to each “why” question leads to an answer that forms the basis of the next question.
The “five” in the name comes from the observation that it often takes about 5 iterations to get to the root cause of a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
